## Hugo A. Matilla Gómez

### **Android Developer**

Address: Plaza Penuelas, 28005, Madrid Tel: 0034619037089

e-mail: hugo.matilla@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 27/01/1981 Nationality: Spanish web: matgom.com

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To be part of the development team and to contribute to with my experience in Android development, and teamwork. I feel extremely motivated to continue improving my career in Android Applications development. Motimate team and its large experience got from Hyper, is a great opportunity to me to keep improving my development skills and, where I could apply my knowledge and motivation to improve the Motimate android applications.

#### **MY PROJECTS**

After almost four years working at Scondoo as main Android Developer and more than one year at SMF, I have been involved in many projects that are now in the Android Play Store. The duration of the developments I have worked on varied from 1 month to more than a year and were undertaken both as solo projects and in teams. I also have some experience in React Native and iOS. Some of the Android projects that can be found in the store include scondoo, HotUkDeals, reBuy, LernCoachies, and DHL.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

EXPERIENCE	
Android Developer scondoo Berlin/Remote. August. 2013 - Present	At scondoo, I overtook with agility and speed the code developed by 2 different agencies. This code was in several cases unstructured. Thanks to my experience I improved it with ease, not only in performance but also in design.  Technical Skills: Android, Java, Kotlin, JSON, Git, JavaScript
Android Developer  HotUKDeals  Berlin. Nov. 2014 – Feb.2015	I worked remotely with the HotUKDeals team in Canada building the new generic app, where I rapidly acquired the knowledge of the software architecture and the team methodologies to help them increase their development process.
	Technical Skills: Android, Java, Clean Architecture
Android Developer Smart Mobile Factory Berlin. May. 2012 – July.2013	My ability to quickly adapt to new concepts has been used to develop and improve various Android Applications. Obstacles I must regularly overcome include definition changes, new features, improvements and tight deadlines.
,	Technical Skills: Android, Java, JSON, XML, Windows Phone, Parse.
Web App & ETL Developer Innova-TSN  Madrid. Jan. 2011 - Feb. 2012	I was quickly integrated into different projects, while experiencing new technical tools, supplying ideas and helping to find solutions. Additionally, I assumed managerial and technical responsibilities and regularly shared my expertise in Oracle with my colleagues.
	Technical Skills: Java, JSP, Html, CSS, Batch, C#, Oracle, Eclipse.
ETL Developer AlamoConsulting	I was part of a small team that developed a large scale corporate DataWarehouse, where versatility was a constant challenge.
Madrid. Jul. 2009 - Dec. 2010	Technical Skills: Oracle, SAS, SAS DIS

#### **EDUCATION**

Postgraduate Studies

**Mobile Development and Services** 

Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia

Madrid. Dec. 2010 - Jul. 2011

Main Subject Areas: Mobile Web and Android Applications

development

**Minor Subject Areas:** Mobile technologies, history, monetization, and IOS development.

**Technical Skills**: HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Java, Android,

Objective-C, IOS.

Main Subject Areas: Programming Methodologies, Software

Engineering, Computer Networks, Operating Systems,

Databases, Computer Architectures,

Minor Subject Areas: Digital Systems, Microcontrollers

Programming.

**Thesis:** Fairness and Market Based Techniques in Wireless

Sensor Networks. Grade 1.3 (TU-Berlin).

# Computer Science Engineering MSc.

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Madrid. Sep. 1999 - Mar. 2009

#### **LANGUAGES**

English	TOEFL Score 94. December 2010.
German	B2 Private School.
Spanish	Mother Tongue.

#### I.T. SKILLS

Languages	Fluent: JAVA, Kotlin, JavaScript.  Basic: Swift, Python, Haskell
WEB	Fluent: HTML5, CSS3, Nodejs.  Basic: React, Meteor, Polymer, WorPress, Jekyll.
Databases	Fluent: SQLite, MongoDB, Oracle.  Basic: Realm, MySQL.
Operating Systems	Fluent: OSX, Windows, Android. Basic: UNIX, iOS.
Documentation	Fluent: UML, E-R. Basic: Gantt.
Agile	Fluent: Kanban, Scrum
Version Control Systems	Fluent: Git

#### **FURTHER INFORMATION**

- Erasmus Programme: TU-Berlin 2007-2009
- Tae-Kwon-Do and Muay Thay black belt.
- Mentor at CoderDojo
- More at <u>hugomatilla.com</u>